(1989年)
斯塔克
Stark!
他看起来不太高兴
He doesn't seem happy.
你好 汉克
Hello, Hank.
你现在应该是在莫斯科的
You're supposed to be in Moscow.
我绕了个道
I took a detour...
经过了你的防御实验室
Through your defense lab.
告诉我这不是我想的那个东西
Tell me that isn't what I think it is.
这取决于你们是否承认在复制我的研究成果
That depends if you think it's a poor attempt to replicate my work.
即使是为了公司 你们也太胆大妄为了
Even for this group, that takes nerve.
你被命令去苏联
You were instructed to go to Russia.
需要我提醒你吗 皮姆博士 你是一名军人…
May I remind you, Dr. Pym, that you're a soldier...
我是科学家
I'm a scientist.
那就表现得像个科学家
Then act like one.
皮姆粒子是最具革命性的研究发现
The Pym Particle is the most revolutionary science ever developed.
帮我们好好利用它
Help us put it to good use.
你把我当成跑腿的也就算了
I let you turn me into your errand boy,
现在你还想偷走我的科研成果吗
and now you try to steal my research?
如果你当初这么拼命地保护珍妮特就好了 皮姆博士
If only you'd protected Janet with such ferocity, Dr. Pym.
冷静点 汉克
Easy, Hank.
你胆敢再提到我的妻子
You mention my wife again
我会让你见识到 什么叫做拼命
and I'll show you ferocity.
别看我 你自己说的
Don't look at me. You said it.
我现在正式提出辞职
I formally tender my resignation.
我们也正式的表示 不接受
We don't accept it. Formally.
汉克
Hank,
我们需要你
we need you.
皮姆粒子是个奇迹 求你了
The Pym Particle is a miracle. Please.
别让你的过去决定你的未来
Don't let your past determine the future.
只要我还活着
As long as I am alive,
没人可以得到那个公式
nobody will ever get that formula.
我们不应该让他离开这座大厦
We shouldn't let him leave the building.
你们已经骗了他 现在还想对他开战吗
You've already lied to him. Now you want to go to war with him?
是的
Yes.
我们的科研人员根本没法复制他的实验成果
Our scientists haven't come close to replicating his work.
相同体型下 你根本不是他的对手
He just kicked your ass, full-size.
你真的想再试试 看不见他是什么情形吗
You really want to find out what it's like when you can't see him coming?
我认识汉克·皮姆很久了
I've known Hank Pym for a long time.
他不是危险分子
He's no security risk.
除非我们激怒了他
Unless we make him one.
(现今)
喜欢吗
You like that?
喜欢就来尝尝
Come get you some now.
你怎么没有反应
You didn't even move.
没反应
Nah.
如果我从左边开打呢 下面这里
What if I come in on the left side, right? Just down here.
你看见这里了吗
You see this right here?
我会想你的 斯科特
I'm gonna miss you, Scott.
我也会想你的 皮奇
I'm gonna miss you, too, Peachy.
伙计 你们的欢送仪式太奇怪了
Man, you guys got the weirdest goodbye rituals.
好啦 散啦
All right, break it up.
散啦 散啦
Break it up! Break it up!
(圣昆廷监狱)
斯科特
Scotty!
怎么了 兄弟
What's up, man!
我靠 嘿
Damn! Hey.
哈哈 嘿 兄弟
Ha-ha! Hey, man.
你眼睛怎么了
Hey, what's up with your eye?
还能怎么样 皮奇干的 算是告别礼物
Oh. Well, what do you think? Peachy. It's a going-away present.
对哦 我一年前留下的伤疤还在呢
Oh, yeah. I still got my scar from a year ago.
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
是
Yeah.
你知道吗 我依旧是唯一将他击倒的人
You know what? I'm still the only one who knocked him out.
好吧 我肯定不行
Well, I definitely didn't.
谢谢你来接我 兄弟
Thanks for picking me up, brother.
兄弟 你觉得我会错过狱友出狱吗
Bro, you think I'm gonna miss my celly getting out?
嘿 你女朋友怎么样了 兄弟
Hey, how's your girl, man?
她把我给甩了
Oh, she left me.
噢
Oh.
是啊 我妈妈死了
Yeah, my ma died, too.
我爸爸也被驱逐出境了
And my dad got deported.
不过我还有这辆面包车
But I got the van!
挺不错的
It's nice.
可不是嘛
Yeah, right?
谢谢你让我借住 我正需要有个地方住呢
Thanks for the hook-up, too. I needed a place to stay.
等到你看见那张沙发再谢我吧 你会非常喜欢的
You wait till you see this couch. You're gonna be really happy.
躺下就不想起来了 看着吧
You're gonna be on your feet in no time. Watch.
- 希望如此 - 是啊
- I hope so. - Yeah.
我还会介绍几个人给你
And I gotta introduce you to some people.
一些技术很棒的人
Some really skilled people.
- 没兴趣 - 好吧
- Not interested. - Yeah, right.
不 我是认真的 兄弟 我可不想再回头了
No, I'm serious, man. I'm not going back.
我有个女儿要照顾
I got a daughter to take care of.
你知道犯有前科的人找工作可不容易 对吧
You know that jobs don't come easy for ex-cons, right?
听着 兄弟 我有电气工程硕士学位
Look, man, I got a master's in electrical engineering, all right?
我会没事的
I'm gonna be fine.
欢迎光临芭斯罗缤
Welcome to Baskin-Robbins.
你想试试我们的芒果冰沙吗
Would you like to try our Mango Fruit Blast?
不用了 谢谢
Uh, no, thanks.
呃 我要一个… 我要一个汉堡 谢谢
Um, I will have... I'll have a burger, please.
我们没有… 我们不卖这个
Oh, we don't... We don't make that.
椒盐卷饼 热的 加芥末的… 你们有芥末蘸酱吗
Pretzel. Hot pretzel. Like, mustard... Do you have mustard dip?
这里是卖冰激凌的 芭斯罗缤
It's ice cream. Baskin-Robbins.
那就 随便来点新鲜出炉的
I'll just do, like, whatever's hot and fresh.
伙计
Dude.
到我办公室来一下 马上
Can I see you in the back, chief? Pronto.
没问题 戴尔
Sure thing, Dale.
戴比 能过来接待一下这个白痴吗 谢谢
Darby, could you just, uh, take care of this idiot? Thanks.
嘿 戴尔
Hey, Dale.
请进
Come on in.
找把椅子坐
Pull up some chair.
在圣昆廷坐了三年牢 对吗
Three years at San Quentin, huh?
你查到了
You found out.
芭斯罗缤总会查到的
Baskin-Robbins always finds out.
听着 我很抱歉 但我…
Look, I'm sorry, all right? But I...
没人愿意雇我
No one would hire me.
非法闯入 重大盗窃案
Breaking and entering. Grand larceny.
听着 我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
- 我不会再干了 我只是… - 向你致意
- I don't do it anymore. I just... - Respect.
我别提有多高兴了
I couldn't be happier about it.
- 真的吗 - 真的
- Really? - Yeah.
谢谢 谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
你肯定教训了那些狗娘养的亿万富翁
You really stuck it to those billionaire SOBs.
我越了解你都做过了些什么…
The more I read about what you did and stuff...
我就越会想 "我居然认识这家伙"
I'm like, "Wow, I know this guy?
"我竟然是这家伙的上司"
"I'm in charge of this guy?"
我做这份工作很开心
Well, I'm very happy in this job,
我很珍惜这个机会…
and I really just appreciate the opportunity to...
当然了 你被开除了
Well, you're fired, of course.
我实在无法留你
I can't really keep you on.
等等 什么 开除
Wait, what? Fired?
是的
Yeah.
戴尔 听着 那不是暴力犯罪 我是个好员工
Dale, look, it wasn't a violent crime. I mean, I'm a good worker.
不 那当然不是暴力犯罪 那是超酷的犯罪
No, it wasn't a violent crime. It was a cool crime.
但我要告诉你
I'll tell you what, though.
这些将不会被记录在案底
This will be totally off the books, off the records,
等一下你卷铺盖走人的时候
but if you want to grab one of those Mango Fruit Blasts
如果想顺走一个芒果冰沙
on your way out the door,
我会假装没看见的
I'll just pretend I didn't see it.
(米格罗姆酒店)
嘿 斯科特 你好啊
Hey, Scotty. What's up?
我还以为你在上班的
I thought you were supposed to be at work.
上了 但我被开除了
I was. I got fired.
该死 他们查到你是谁了吗
Damn. They find out who you are?
是的
Yeah.
芭斯罗缤总会查到的 兄弟
Baskin-Robbins always finds out, bro.
芭斯罗缤可不是闹着玩的
Baskin-Robbins don't play.
你要来点华夫饼吗
You want some waffles?
好啊 那就来点华夫饼
Yeah, I'll take a waffle.
那是库尔特
Oh. That's Kurt.
他在福尔瑟姆监狱待了五年 他可是个电脑奇才
He was Folsom for five years. He's a wizard on that laptop.
很高兴认识你
Nice meet you.
认识你我也很高兴
Yeah. Nice to meet you, too.
你是谁
Who are you?
戴夫
Dave.
维斯塔公司那一票干得漂亮
Nice work on the Vista job.
维斯塔那票 对
Vista job, yes.
我听说过那起抢劫
No, no. I have heard of this robbery.
严格来说 我没有抢劫 抢劫涉及威胁
Well, technically, I didn't rob them. Robbery involves threat.
我讨厌暴力 我那叫入室盗窃 我只是个飞贼
I hate violence. I burgled them. I'm a cat burglar.
你意思是 你是个娘们
You mean you're a pussy.
好吧
Yeah.
维斯塔公司高价宰客 对吧
They were overcharging the customers, right?
加起来有几百万了
And it added up to millions.
他揭发后却被开除了
He blows the whistle and he gets fired.
然后你猜他怎么着
And what does he do?
他黑进了公司的安全系统
He hacks into the security system
把那几百万转账还给了那些被坑的客户
and transfers millions back to the people that they stole it from.
还把所有的银行交易记录发布到了网上
Posts all the bank records online.
然后他开着那家伙的宾利冲进了他的游泳池里
And he drove the dude's Bentley into his swimming pool.
你这是在干嘛
What are you doing?
为什么把我的事告诉这些人
Why are you telling my life story to these guys?
你想干什么
What do you want?
好吧
Okay.
我表哥两周前跟这家伙谈过
My cousin talked to this guy two weeks ago
是个超级棒的小活
about this little perfect job.
没门
No way.
不不不 等等 那家伙… 那家伙完全对你的口味
No, no, no. Wait! This guy... This guy fits your M.O.
不行
No!
我金盆洗手了 兄弟 我不想再回监狱里去了
I'm finished, man. I'm not going back to jail.
是个靠退休金生活的百万富翁
It's some retired millionaire living off his golden parachute.
这可是斯科特·朗的完美目标
It's a perfect Scott Lang mark!
我不在乎 我不干
I don't care. I'm out.
皮姆博士
Dr. Pym?
是的 我还活着
Yes. I'm still alive.
身份卡
ID?
那个应该就能证明了
Perhaps that will suffice.
非常抱歉 先生 请进
Very sorry, sir. Please come in.
那是汉克·皮姆吗
Is that Hank Pym?
早上好 汉克
Good morning, Hank.
霍普
Hope.
叫我一声爸爸会死吗
Would it kill you to call me Dad?
克罗斯博士肯定非常高兴
Dr. Cross will be so pleased that
今天你能过来加入我们
you could find the time to join us today.
更确切的说是:"欣喜若狂"
More like "thrilled."
我很意外能收到你发来的邀请信 达伦
I was surprised to receive any kind of invitation from you, Darren.
今天是什么日子
What's the occasion?
一会你就知道 对吗 霍普
Oh, you'll see. Won't he, Hope?
我们在里面已经为你准备好了
We're ready for you inside.
哎呦
Ouch.
我猜有些旧伤口愈合不了 对吗
I guess some old wounds never heal, huh?
别担心 她会得到很好的照顾
Don't worry, she's in good hands.
你会喜欢的
You're in for a treat.
好久不见 皮姆博士 退休生活还好吗
Long time, no see, Dr. Pym. How's retirement?
你的脸还好吗
How's your face?
你先请
After you.
在我们开始之前 我想先介绍一位特殊来宾
Now, before we start, I'd like to introduce a very special guest.
本公司的创始人 也是我的导师
This company's founder and my mentor,
汉克·皮姆博士
Dr. Hank Pym.
当我从皮姆博士那里接手这家公司后
When I took over this company for Dr. Pym,
我立即开始研究一种
I immediately started researching a particle
能够改变原子间距离
that could change the distance between atoms,
同时能增加密度和强度的粒子
while increasing density and strength.
为什么这个革命性创意一直被
Why this revolutionary idea remained buried
汉克雪藏在灰尘和蛛网之下
beneath the dust and cobwebs of
我没法告诉你们
Hank's research, I couldn't tell you.
不过设想一下
But just imagine,
一个昆虫般大小的战士
a soldier the size of an insect.
一件终极秘密武器
The ultimate secret weapon.
一个蚁人
An Ant-Man.
他们以前就这么称呼你的 对吧 汉克
That's what they called you. Right, Hank?
很傻的名字 我知道
Silly, I know.
宣传需要罢了
Propaganda.
类似惊奇故事
Tales to astonish!
胡编乱造用来吓唬苏联人
Trumped-up BS to scare the USSR.
汉克 你可否告诉客人们
Hank, will you tell our guests what you told me
每次我问你"真的有蚁人吗"时
every single time I asked you,
你是如何回答的
"Was the Ant-Man real?"
只是个传说罢了
Just a tall tale.
没错
Right.
因为这么神奇的东西怎么可能会是真的呢
Because how could anything so miraculous possibly be real?
但我被蚁人的传说激发了灵感
Well, I was inspired by the legend of the Ant-Man.
随着我在非有机材料缩小技术上有所突破
And with my breakthrough shrinking inorganic material,
我就在想 缩小人类是否可行
I thought, could it be possible to shrink a person?
究竟能不能做到
Could that be done?
其实那已不再是传说
Well, it's not a legend anymore.
尊敬的客人们
Distinguished guests,
我骄傲的向你们展示当代战争的终结者
I am proud to present the end of warfare as we know it.
黄蜂战衣
The Yellowjacket!
哦 不
Oh, no.
黄蜂战衣是一种全能的战争武器
The Yellowjacket is an all-purpose weapon of war
可以改变穿戴者的大小
capable of altering the size of the wearer
以获得终极的战斗优势
for the ultimate combat advantage.
我们生活在
We live in an era
一个用武器自卫却不断受到
in which the weapons we use to protect ourselves
实时监控破坏的时代
are undermined by constant surveillance.
是时候回归更简单的时代了
It's time to return to a simpler age.
一个可以用自由力量光明正大
One where the powers of freedom can once again operate openly
保护自身权益的时代
to protect their interests.
作为一件全能型和平卫士的可穿戴物
An all-purpose peace-keeping vessel,
黄蜂战衣可以应付
the Yellowjacket can manage any conflict
地缘政治环境中的任何冲突
on the geopolitical landscape
而不被发现
completely unseen.
高效执行预防性举措和战术性进攻
Efficient in both preventative measures and tactical assault.
实用范围包括监视
Practical applications include surveillance,
工业破坏
industrial sabotage,
以及铲除通往和平途中的所有障碍
and the elimination of obstructions on the road to peace.
一件黄蜂战衣
A single Yellowjacket
使用者就可以拥有无限潜能
offers the user unlimited influence
以实施防御举措
to carry out protective actions.
不久的将来 一个黄蜂战衣的军队
And, one day soon, an army of Yellowjackets
将会在全世界创造出一个
will create a sustainable environment
幸福安康的可持续环境
of well-being around the world.
黄蜂战衣
The Yellowjacket.
所以 只是件衣服
So, it's a suit?
别那么轻率 弗兰克
Don't be crude, Frank.
这可不是普通的衣服 而是载体
It's not a suit, it's a vessel.
怎么了 没能打动你吗
What's the matter? You're not impressed?
不 不只打动了我 还把我吓到了
No, I'm impressed. I'm also concerned.
想象一下 如果我们的敌人掌握了这种技术会干出什么
Imagine what our enemies could do with this tech.
这个问题我们回头再详细谈 弗兰克
We should have a longer conversation about that, Frank.
我真的很重视你的意见
I really value your opinion.
谢谢各位的到来 霍普
Thank you for coming. Hope?
非常感谢大家 我送你们出去
Thank you very much, everybody. I will escort you out now.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看起来有点震惊
You seem a bit shocked.
达伦 我当初把这秘密埋藏起来是有原因的
Darren, there's a reason that I buried these secrets.
所以你终于承认了
So you finally admit it!
我们本来可以合作的 汉克 可你把那机会毁掉了
We could have done this together, Hank. But you ruined that.
因此你是过去 而我将是未来
That's why you're the past and I'm the future.
停手吧
Don't do this.
克罗斯博士
Dr. Cross?
你先卖给我 价钱可以再多给你百分之二十
You sell to me first, 20% over your asking price,
两周之内你就可以拿到现金
I can have the cash here in two weeks.
成交
Deal.
我们得采取行动了 汉克
We have to make our move, Hank.
他进展到哪一步了
How close is he?
他仍然不能缩小活物
He still can't shrink a live subject.
把套战服给我 让我彻底了结这事
Just give me the suit and let me finish this once and for all.
不行
No.
克罗斯现在完全信任我
I have Cross' complete trust.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
我们没有选择
We don't have a choice.
话可别说得那么绝对
Well, that's not entirely true.
我想我有人选了
I think I found a guy.
谁
Who?
爸爸
Daddy!
小花生 哦
Peanut! Oh!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
真抱歉我来晚了
I'm so sorry I'm late.
我不知道聚会几点开始
I didn't know what time your party started.
请柬上有写啊
It was on the invitation.
没给他发请柬
He didn't get an invitation.
但他还是来了
But he came anyway!
我可不想错过我宝贝女儿的生日派对
Well, I'm not gonna miss my little girl's birthday party.
我去告诉妈妈你来了
I'm gonna go tell Mommy you're here.
你别…
Oh, you don't...
你来这里干嘛 朗
What are you doing here, Lang?
孩子的抚养费你一毛钱都没给过
You haven't paid a dime of child support.
你知道吗 如果我愿意 现在就可以逮捕你
You know, right now, if I wanted to, I could arrest you.
很高兴见到你 帕克斯顿
It's good to see you too, Paxton.
妈妈听说你来了 高兴得喝水都呛着了
Mommy's so happy you're here, she choked on her drink.
看看我给你带了什么
Hey, look what I have for you.
我现在能打开吗
Can I open it now?
当然了 小宝贝 今天是你生日
Of course, sweetheart. It's your birthday.
你是我最最好的朋友
You're my bestest friend.
这什么玩意
What is that thing?
他好丑
He's so ugly!
我爱死他了
I love him!
我能拿去给小伙伴们看吗
Can I go show my friends?
当然 宝贝儿 去吧
Of course, sweetheart. Go ahead.
你是我最最好的朋友
You're my bestest friend.
听着 孩子的抚养费我会给你的 好吗
Look, the child support is coming, all right?
只是有前科的人找工作不容易
It's just hard finding a job when you have a record.
我相信你会有办法的 但是现在 我要你离开我家
I'm sure you'll figure it out. But for now, I want you out of my house.
- 不可能 今天是我女儿生日 - 这是我家
- No way! It's my daughter's birthday. - It's my house!
- 那又怎样 她是我的孩子 - 斯科特
- So what? It's my kid! - Scott!
你不能想来就来 你知道的 走吧
You can't just show up here. You know that. Come on.
可这是生日聚会
It's a birthday party.
是 我知道 那你也不能想来就来
Yeah, I know, but you can't just show up.
她是我女儿
She's my daughter.
你根本不知道如何做父亲
You don't know the first thing about being a father.
玛姬 我以朋友的身份
Maggie, I tell you this as a friend,
并看在你是我初恋的份上告诉你
and as the first love of my life.
你未婚夫是个傻帽
Your fiance is an asshat.
他不是傻帽
He's not an asshat.
嘿 说话注意点 行吗
Hey, watch your language. Okay?
说话怎么了 我说的是"帽"
What language? I said "hat."
住嘴
Stop it.
你是认真的吗 玛姬 就那家伙
Really, Maggie? That guy?
拜托 你嫁给谁不行
Come on! You could marry anyone you want,
偏偏要嫁给警察
and you have to get engaged to a cop?
至少他不是罪犯
At least he's not a crook.
我在努力 好吗 我改了 改邪归正了
I'm trying, okay? I've changed. I'm straight.
我有过工作而且…
I had a job and...
我想要抚养女儿
I wanna provide.
我花了很多时间考虑过 并且我爱她
I had a lot of time to think about it and I love her.
非常爱
So much.
我错过了太多时间 我想成为她生活的一部分
I've missed so much time and I wanna be a part of her life.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
租个房子
Get an apartment,
找个工作 付抚养费
get a job, pay child support.
那时我们再来谈探视权 我保证
And then we will talk about visitation, I promise.
你是她的英雄 斯科特
You're her hero, Scott.
好好保持你在她心目中的形象
Just be the person that she already thinks you are.
我很抱歉让你对黄蜂战衣担忧了 弗兰克
I'm sorry you have such deep concerns about the Yellowjacket, Frank.
是啊…
Yeah. Well, uh...
可惜 我们都不能为所欲为
Unfortunately, we can't just do whatever we want.
那倒是好 对吧
It'd be nice though, right?
但还是要遵从法律
But there are laws.
什么法律 人类的
What laws? Of man?
自然的法则高于人类的法律
The laws of nature transcend the laws of man.
而我已经超越了自然的法则
And I've transcended the laws of nature.
达伦 看来你没明白…
Darren, I don't think you understand...
嗯
Hmm.
看来我们的技术仍有漏洞
We still haven't worked out all the bugs.
再见了 弗兰克
Goodbye, Frank.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗 我最近经常思考感恩的含义
You know, I've been thinking a lot about gratitude lately.
今天我晨间冥想时
And today, during my morning meditation,
产生了个有趣的想法
an interesting thought occurred to me,
我觉得也适用于你
and I think it might apply to you, too.
此话怎讲
How's that?
感恩可以是宽恕
Gratitude can be forgiveness.
这么多年来我一直在生汉克·皮姆的气
I've spent years carrying around my anger for Hank Pym.
我把自己的才华都贡献给了他
I devoted my genius to him.
本来我去哪工作都可以
I could have worked anywhere.
我偏偏没选好导师
I chose my mentor poorly.
而你却连选择都没有
You didn't even have a choice.
他从不信任你
He never believed in you.
虽然我为咱们所做的事感到惭愧
It's a shame what we had to do,
但都是他逼的 对吧
but he forced us to do it, didn't he?
但我们不应该愤怒 而是应该感恩
But we shouldn't be angry, we should be grateful.
因为他是一个失败的导师
Because his failures as a mentor,
一个失败的父亲
as a father,
是他逼得我们展翅高飞
forced us to spread our wings.
你是成功的 达伦
You're a success, Darren.
将来的一切都是你应得的
You deserve everything coming your way.
(377天后才能见凯茜)
哦
Ooh.
别耍赖
Stop cheating.
嘿 回来了 高手
Hey, what's up, hotshot?
他可能没听见
Maybe he didn't hear you.
聚会还好吗
How was the party?
跟我说说那一票应该怎么干
Tell me about that tip.
什么
What?
我想知道那一票应该怎么干
I wanna know about that tip.
噢 宝贝儿 开工了 立刻开工
Oh, baby, it's on! It's so on, right now.
先别激动 好吗 我需要知道这票到底是什么来头
Calm down, all right? I just need to know where it came from.
必须做得天衣无缝
It's gotta be airtight.
好吧
Okay.
我在一个品酒会上遇到了我表哥埃内斯托
I was at a wine tasting with my cousin Ernesto.
主要是红酒 你知道我不太喜欢喝红酒的 哥们
Which was mainly reds, and you know I don't like reds, man.
但那天有一种桃红酒 非常好喝
But there was a rose that saved the day. It was delightful.
然后他跟我提到了一个女孩
And then he tells me about this girl,
叫艾米丽 我们以前泡过的妞
Emily, that we used to kick it with.
其实我第一次摸到的胸部就是她的
It was actually the first pair of boobs I ever touched.
我不想听这些细节
It's the wrong details.
这些都跟主题无关
It has nothing to do with the story.
继续说
Go.
他跟我说 那个叫艾米丽的
So, uh, he tells me that she's
她现在当钟点工 知道吗
working as a housekeeper now, right?
然后她跟一个叫卡洛斯的搞对象
And she's dating this dude, Carlos,
他是湾区那边的一个帮派头子
who's a shot caller from across the bay.
她把雇主家的情况全盘告诉给了卡洛斯
And she tells him about the dude that she's cleaning for.
对吧 那雇主好像是一个大公司的总裁
Right? That he's like this big-shot CEO
现在退休了 但有的是钱
that is all retired now, but he's loaded.
然后 卡洛斯和埃内斯托是同一个垒球队的
And so, Carlos and Ernesto are on the same softball team,
于是他们聊开了 懂吗
and they get to talking, right?
接下来就是重头戏了 卡洛斯说 嘿 伙计
And here comes the good part. Carlos says, "Yo, man.
那家伙有个体积巨大的保险箱
This guy's got a big-ass safe just
就在地下室里 简直棒极了
sitting in the basement, just chilling."
毫无疑问埃内斯托把这件事告诉了我
Of course Ernesto comes to me because
因为他知道我偷盗技术了得
he knows I got mad thieving skills.
然后 我问他
Of course, I ask him...
艾米丽有没有通过卡洛斯告诉你
"Did Emily tell Carlos to tell you
保险箱是什么样的
"to get to me what kind of safe it was?"
然后他说 没有 老兄
And he says, "Nah, dawg.
她只说是个超级坚固的那种
All she said is that it's super-legit
不管里面是什么 肯定很值钱
and whatever's in it, it's gotta be good."
什么
What?
老头子有个保险箱
Old man have safe.
而且他要外出一星期
And he's gone for a week.
明白了 一个老头 他有个保险箱
All right. There's an old man, he's got a safe,
而且他要外出一星期
and he's gone for a week.
来吧 干他一票
Let's just work with that.
我就是这个意思
You know what I'm saying?
座机信号切断了 手机信号也瘫痪了
Landline's cut, cell signal's jammed.
今晚没人能报警了
No one will be making for distress call tonight.
通讯检查
Comm check.
- 检查 - 检查
- Check. - Check.
如果你失手了 别忘了你还有我这个后援
Hey, if the job goes bad, you know I got your back, right?
不用担心
Don't worry.
不会有这种事的
It's not gonna happen.
我就是喜欢他自信满满的样子
I love it when he gets cocky.
厉害
Damn!
报警系统给废了
Alarm is dead.
干得漂亮
Nice.
好了 我正在穿过房间
All right, I'm moving through the house.
门上有个指纹锁
There's a fingerprint lock on the door.
有个什么 埃内斯托可没告诉我这些
It's got what? Ernesto didn't tell me nothing about that.
兄弟 我们没戏了吗
Aw, man, are we screwed?
那可不一定
Not necessarily.
我进来了
I'm in.
没有触发警报 对他而言简直是小菜一碟
No alarms have been triggered. He's in like the Flynn.
哦 天呐
Oh, man.
怎么了
What is it?
看来他们没骗我们 这保险箱真是固若金汤
Well, they weren't kidding. This safe is serious.
有多坚固 斯科特
How serious are we talking, Scotty?
产自卡本代尔
It's a Carbondale.
1910年生产的
It's from 1910.
和泰坦尼克号用的同样的材料
Made from the same steel as the Titanic.
哇哦
Wow.
你能打开它吗
Can you crack it?
是这样的 这玩意耐寒性不怎么样
Well, here's the thing. It doesn't do so well in the cold.
还记得撞冰山的事情吗
Remember what that iceberg did?
当然了 伙计 把小李子给淹死了
Yeah, man. It killed DiCaprio.
淹死了所有人
Killed everybody.
没有淹死那个老太太
Did not kill the old lady.
她最后还把宝石扔到海里了
She still throw the jewel into the oceans.
你做了什么
What are you doing?
我往锁芯里注水 然后用液氮冷冻
I poured water in the locking mechanism and froze it with nitrogen.
冰会膨胀 金属可不会
Ice expands. Metal doesn't.
- 那你现在在干嘛 - 在等
- What are you doing now? - Waiting.
在等
Waiting.
不错
Nice.
里面有什么 钞票 珠宝
What is it? Cash? Jewels?
- 里面什么都没有 - 你说什么
- There's nothing here. - What did you say?
只有一套衣服
It's a suit.
什么
What?
是一套旧的机车服
It's an old motorcycle suit.
没有钞票 没有珠宝 什么都没有吗
There's no cash, no jewelry, nothing?
没有
No.
我们扑了个空
It's a bust.
真是对不住 斯科特
I'm really sorry, Scotty.
我明白你想要捞一票
I know you needed to score.
我以为我们要用老鼠
I thought we were using mice.
有什么区别吗
What's the difference?
准备34-C号实验 缩小有机原子
Commence Experiment 34-C. Organic atomic reduction.
达伦 也许我们该再考虑一下
Darren, maybe we should think...
缩小有机组织是这项技术的核心
Shrinking organic tissue is the centerpiece of this technology.
我可不能把半成品交给买家
I can't go to the buyers with half a breakthrough.
34-C号试验
Experiment 34-C results,
失败
negative.
给实验台消毒 把35-C号实验对象带来
Sanitize the work station. Bring in subject 35-C.
为什么你会把这个锁起来
Why would you lock this up?
真是奇怪
This is so weird.
怎么了 斯科特
Scotty, what's up, man?
我想知道 这是什么
I wonder... What is this?
从这个角度看世界
The world sure seems different
还真是不一样 是不是 斯科特
from down here, doesn't it, Scott?
什么 谁在说话
What? Who said that?
路易斯 我在下面
Luis, down here!
这是一次艰难的考验 斯科特 或者说
It's a trial by fire, Scott. Or, in this case,
是来自水的考验
water.
看来你比想象中的要厉害
Guess you're tougher than you thought.
我可不想看你脱衣服
Oh, I don't want to see this!
路易斯
Luis!
混蛋
Son of a...
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
初次试验还不错
Not bad for a test drive.
保管好衣服 我还会和你联系的
Keep the suit. I'll be in touch.
不 不 不 不用了
No! No! No, thank you!
趴在地上
Get down on the ground!
你被捕了
You are under arrest!
我没有偷东西 我是来还我偷的东西
No, I didn't steal anything! I was returning something I stole.
哦
Oh...
不许动
Don't move.
你知道吗 我们差点都相信
You know, you almost had us convinced
你改过自新了
that you were gonna change your ways.
母女俩都很看好你
They were really rooting for you.
这会伤了她们的心的
It's gonna break their hearts.
有人来探视你了
You got a visitor.
谁
Who?
你的律师
Your lawyer.
我的律师
My lawyer?
我说过我还会跟你联系的 斯科特
I told you I'd be in touch, Scott.
我在想你是不是比较喜欢蹲局子
I'm starting to think that you prefer the inside of a jail cell.
天呐
Oh, man.
坐吧
Sit down.
先生 我很抱歉我偷了你的衣服
Sir, I'm sorry I stole the suit.
我甚至不知道为什么你会拥有那件衣服
I don't even wanna know why you have it.
玛姬没看错你
Maggie was right about you.
你怎么知道玛姬
How do you know about...
难怪她不让你接近凯茜
No wonder she's trying to keep you away from Cassie.
每当事情得不到很好的解决
The moment things get hard,
你就会走老路去犯罪
you turn right back to crime.
不过要我说 你还是有选择的余地的
The way I see it, you have a choice.
要么你选择在监狱里度过余生
You can either spend the rest of your life in prison,
要么你先回拘留室
or go back to your cell
等我下一步的指令
and await further instructions.
我没搞明白
I don't understand.
我也没指望你明白
No, I don't expect you to.
不过你现在没别的选择了 而且老实说
But you don't have many options right now, and quite frankly,
我也一样
neither do I.
难道你没想过 一开始就是我布局让你偷战服的吗
Why do you think I let you steal that suit in the first place?
什么
What?
这样的机会可不是经常都有的
Second chances don't come around all that much.
所以 如果你遇到了这样的机会
So, next time you think you might see one,
我建议你最好认真仔细的考虑一下
I suggest you take a real close look at it.
你是我最好的朋友
You're my bestest friend!
你真的不要换一个玩具吗
Are you sure you don't want a different toy?
不 我就喜欢这个
No, I love this one.
好吧 快睡吧 我爱你
Okay. Well, get some sleep. I love you.
- 妈妈 - 怎么了
- Mommy? - Hmm?
爸爸真的是坏人吗
Is Daddy a bad man?
我听一些大人说他很坏
I heard some grownups say he's bad.
不是的
No.
爸爸只是有时候犯糊涂 你明白吗
Daddy just gets confused sometimes, you know?
明智的选择 你终于开窍了
Smart choice. You actually listened, for once.
从门下面走
Under the door.
好了 现在去哪
Okay, where to now?
- 稍等 - 哦 天呐
- Hang tight. - Oh, God.
什么 你说什么
What, what?
他到底跑哪去了
Where the hell did he go?
我不知道 他就这么凭空消失了
I have no idea. He just vanished.
立刻封锁附近五个街区 马上
Set up a five-block perimeter. Now!
退后 退后
Get back! Get back!
斯科特 这些是我的伙伴
Scott, these are my associates.
蚂蚁身上装了摄像头吗
Is that a camera on an ant?
是啊 不然呢
Yeah, sure. Why not?
车在哪里
Where's the car?
没有车 我们用翅膀
No car. We've got wings.
来了
Incoming!
脚踩在中间那节 然后骑到它胸部
Put your foot on the central node and mount the thorax.
- 这玩意安全 - 赶紧骑上去 斯科特
- How safe is... - Just get on the damn ant, Scott!
我怎么在警车上
Why am I on a police car?
我不是不应该在警车上吗
Shouldn't I not be on a police car?
这样你们就能搭顺风车
So they can give you a lift
穿过五个街区的封锁了
past their five-block perimeter.
好吧
All right.
- 接下来怎么做 - 抓牢
- Now, what's the next move? - Hang on tight.
这挺简单的嘛 我已经能控制它了
Oh, this is easy! I'm getting the hang of this.
想往上飞就往上拉 就像骑马一样
Yank up to go up. It's like a horse.
你让247快要失去平衡了
You're throwing 247 off balance.
等等 他叫247
Wait, his name is 247?
他没有名字 只有编号 斯科特
He doesn't have a name, he has a number, Scott.
你知道一共有多少蚂蚁吗
Do you have any idea how many ants there are?
哦
Whoa!
也有可能它是 可能它是248
Maybe it's... Maybe it's 248.
别 别 好晕 好晕
No, no! Vertigo, vertigo!
不 我认为它就是247
No, I think it's 247.
等等
Wait.
抓紧点
Hang on tight!
我想我找到控制它的窍门了
I think I'm getting the hang of this.
是我在控制247 它不听你的
I am controlling 247. He is not listening to you.
什么
What?
- 我能提一点小小的要求吗 - 不能
- Can I make one little request? - No.
停下 247 先停一下 先停一下
Stop, 247! Time out, time out.
停一下
Time out.
好了 抓紧了
All right, hold on.
等一下 哦
Just wait! Whoa!
如果我吐在头盔里怎么办
What happens if I throw up in this helmet?
那是我的头盔 斯科特 你不准吐
It's my helmet, Scott. You do not throw up.
让她把我放下来 行吗
Let's set her down, all right?
我已经开始头晕了
I'm getting light-headed.
坚持住 斯科特
Hang on, Scott.
我真的有点晕了
I'm getting a little light...
我得小睡一会
I need a snooze button.
五分钟后叫我
Hit me in 5 minutes.
你好
Hello.
你是谁
Who are you?
你一直站在这里 看着我睡觉吗
Have you been standing there, watching me sleep, this whole time?
没错
Yes.
为什么
Why?
因为你上次来的时候 偷走了一件东西
Because the last time you were here, you stole something.
哦 哦
Oh. Oh.
听我说
Hey, look...
哦
Whoa!
学名 帕拉珀尼拉克拉瓦塔
Paraponera clavata.
是一种长得像子弹的巨型热带蚂蚁
Giant tropical bullet ants,
在施密特刺痛指数中位列第一
ranked highest on the Schmidt pain index.
我不在的时候它们会在这看着你
They're here to keep an eye on you when I can't.
皮姆博士在楼下等你
Dr. Pym's waiting for you downstairs.
谁？
Who?
嘿
Hey!
呃… 这是谁的睡裤？
Um... Whose pajamas are these?
这要怎么过去？
How am I supposed to do this?
好吧 一步一步慢慢走
All right, just one step at a time.
你们不咬我 我就不踩你们 好吧？
You don't bite me, I don't step on you. Deal?
我可以拆除服务器
I could take down the servers
克罗斯不会发现的
and Cross wouldn't even know it.
我们不需要这家伙
We don't need this guy.
我想你已经见过我女儿霍普了
I assume that you've already met my daughter, Hope.
是的 她人很好
I did. She's great.
她觉得我们不需要你
She doesn't think that we need you.
不需要 我们可以自己解决
We don't. We can do this ourselves.
我费尽心思让你来偷我的战衣
I go to all this effort to let you steal my suit,
然后霍普再让你被捕
and then Hope has you arrested.
好吧 我们可以让他试试 如果失败了 我就亲自出马
Okay, we can try this and when he fails, I'll do it myself.
她有点焦虑
She's a little bit anxious.
和这次任务有关
It has to do with this job,
鉴于你已经坐在我对面了
which, judging by the fact that you're sitting opposite me,
我猜你会对它感兴趣的
I take it that you're interested in.
什么任务？
What job?
想来点茶么？
Would you like some tea?
好的
Uh... Sure.
我对你成功突破我的安保系统
I was very impressed with
印象深刻
how you managed to get past my security system.
冰冻金属门那一招很聪明
Freezing that metal was particularly clever.
你在监视我？
Were you watching me?
斯科特 我已经监视你好一段时间了
Scott, I've been watching you for a while.
从你抢劫维斯塔公司开始
Ever since you robbed Vista Corp.
哦 抱歉
Oh! Excuse me.
应该说"偷"
"Burgled" Vista Corp.
维斯塔的安保系统是业界
Vista's security system was one of
最先进的系统之一
the most advanced in the business.
本应固若金汤
It was supposed to be unbeatable.
但还是被你成功突破了
But you beat it.
要加点糖吗？
Would you like some sugar?
好的 谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
还是不要了
You know what? I'm okay.
你是怎么让它们做到的？
How do you make them do that?
蚂蚁可以举起它们体重五十倍的东西
Ants can lift objects 50 times their weight.
它们筑巢 翻土 它们之间相互配合
They build, farm, they cooperate with each other.
我知道 但你怎么让它们做到的？
Right. But how do you make them do that?
我用电磁波刺激它们的嗅觉神经中枢
I use electromagnetic waves to stimulate their olfactory nerve center.
和它们讲话
I speak to them.
我无所不在
I can go anywhere, hear anything,
眼观六路 耳听八方
and see everything.
但仍然一无所知
And still know absolutely nothing.
我见克罗斯要迟到了
I'm late to meet Cross.
呃… 皮姆博士？
Uh... Dr. Pym?
你不用举手的 斯科特
You don't need to raise your hand, Scott.
抱歉 我有个问题
Sorry, I just have one question.
你是谁 她又是谁 这到底什么情况
Who are you, who is she, what the hell's going on,
还有我现在可以回去坐牢了吗？
and can I go back to jail now?
跟我来
Come with me.
四十年前 我发明了一个公式
40 years ago, I created a formula
可以改变原子之间的相对距离
that altered atomic relative distance.
什么？
Huh?
我在研究如何改变原子之间的距离
I learned how to change the distance between atoms.
也是这套战衣的威力所在
That's what powers the suit.
这就是它工作的原理
That's why it works.
哇
Wow.
- 哇 - 但是它很危险
- Whoa! - But it was dangerous.
非常危险
It was too dangerous.
所以我只能将它隐匿于世
So I hid it from the world.
后来我转而开办了自己的公司
And that's when I switched gears and I started my own company.
皮姆科技
Pym Tech.
没错
Yes.
我收了一个年轻学生叫达伦·克罗斯
I took on a young protege called Darren Cross.
达伦·克罗斯
Darren Cross.
他可是个风云人物
He's a big deal.
在他成为风云人物之前 还只是我的助手
But before he was a big deal, he was my assistant.
我在他身上看到一些特质 我从没见过这样的孩子
I thought I saw something in him. The son I never had, perhaps.
他很聪明 但随着我们越来越亲近
He was brilliant, but as we became close,
他开始怀疑我对他有所隐瞒
he began to suspect that I wasn't telling him everything.
他听到有关皮姆粒子的传言
He heard rumors about what was called the Pym Particle,
于是他沉迷于想复制我的公式
and he became obsessed with recreating my formula.
但是我不愿意帮他
But I wouldn't help him.
所以他密谋反对我 投票把我赶出了我的公司
So he conspired against me and he voted me out of my own company.
他怎么做到的？
How could he do that?
董事会主席是我的女儿 霍普
The board's chairman is my daughter, Hope.
她投了决定票
She was the deciding vote.
但是当她看到克罗斯就要破解我的公式时
But she came back to me
她又回到我身边
when she saw how close Cross was to cracking my formula.
他的研究过程很不稳定
The process is highly volatile.
如果没有专业头盔的保护
If one isn't protected by a specialized helmet,
将会影响大脑化学反应
it can affect the brain's chemistry.
我觉得达伦还没意识到这一点
I don't think Darren realizes this,
你知道 他原本就不是个稳重的人
and, you know, he's not the most stable guy to begin with.
所以 你们想要我干什么？
So, what do you want from me?
斯科特 我相信每个人都应有自我救赎的机会
Scott, I believe that everyone deserves a shot at redemption.
你信吗？
Do you?
是的 我信
I do.
如果你可以帮我
If you can help me,
我保证 我可以让你和女儿重新团聚
I promise I can help you be with your daughter again.
现在 你准备好自我救赎了吗？
Now, are you ready to redeem yourself?
当然
Absolutely.
我私闯民宅偷东西的日子 已经一去不复返了
My days of breaking into places and stealing shit are done.
需要我做什么？
What do you want me to do?
我想让你私闯民宅偷东西
I want you to break into a place and steal some shit.
你今天晚上回家吃饭吗？
Are you gonna be home for dinner tonight?
(朗的"律师"是皮姆科技的汉克皮姆博士)
是的 我有点事 短信联系
Uh, yeah. I'll pick something up. Text me.
好的 是好消息吗？
Okay. Good news?
呃… 我也不知道 只是个消息
Uh... I don't know. It's news.
你在找我爸爸吗？
Are you trying to find my daddy?
是 是的 小甜心
Yeah, I am, sweetheart.
我只是想你爸爸安然无恙
I just want your daddy to be safe.
但愿你抓不到他
Hope you don't catch him.
这些人已经不是第一次
This isn't the first time these guys
想要控制改变世界格局的新型武器了
have tried to get their hands on game-changing weaponry.
这是米切尔·卡森 神盾局前防卫部部长
That's Mitchell Carson, Ex-Head of Defense at S.H.I.E.L.D.
现在正致力于四处推翻政权
Presently in the business of toppling governments.
他一直觊觎我的技术
He always wanted my tech.
现在 除非我们溜进去偷出黄蜂战衣
And now, unless we break in and steal the Yellowjacket
摧毁所有的数据
and destroy all the data,
否则达伦·克罗斯会在全世界引发混乱
Darren Cross is gonna unleash chaos upon the world.
我觉得 我们首先应该通知复仇者联盟
I think our first move should be calling the Avengers.
我花费大半生精力
I spent half my life
不让这项技术落入斯塔克之手
trying to keep this technology out of the hands of a Stark.
我现在当然更不会把这项技术拱手让人
I'm sure as hell not gonna hand-deliver it to one now.
这可不是钢铁侠盔甲那种花哨的技术
This is not some cute technology like the Iron Man suit.
这是可以改变现实结构的技术
This could change the texture of reality.
况且 他们可能正忙着
Besides, they're probably too busy
把一座座城市从天上往下扔呢
dropping cities out of the sky.
好吧 那你为什么不直接派你的蚂蚁去？
Okay, then why don't you just send the ants?
斯科特 它们只是蚂蚁
Scott, they are ants.
蚂蚁虽然可以做很多事情 但它们需要一个领导者
Ants, they can do a lot of things, but they still need a leader.
一个可以
Somebody that could infiltrate a place
无孔不入的人
that's designed to prevent infiltration.
汉克 我只是一个小偷 好吗？我是说
Hank, I'm a thief, all right? I mean,
尽管我是高明的小偷 但这也太疯狂了
I'm a good thief, but this is insane.
他说的没错 汉克 我想你也明白
He's right, Hank. And you know it.
你已经看了录像 知道克罗斯的神通本事了
You've seen the footage, you know what Cross is capable of.
几个月前我就反对用他
I was against using him when we had months,
而现在我们只剩几天了
and now we have days.
我来穿这套战衣
I'm wearing the suit.
绝对不行
Absolutely not!
我知道里面所有机关 我也知道克罗斯的想法
I know the facility inside and out. I know how Cross thinks.
我比任何人都了解这项任务
I know this mission better than anybody here.
我们需要你紧跟在克罗斯身边 否则任务没法完成
We need you close to Cross. Otherwise, this mission cannot work.
- 我们没有时间瞎折腾了 - 霍普 认真听我说…
- We don't have time to screw around! - Hope, please listen to me...
他是一个罪犯 我可是你女儿
He is a criminal! I'm your daughter.
不行
No!
她说得对 汉克
She's right, Hank.
我不是最佳人选
I'm not your guy.
你为什么不穿这套战服呢？
Why don't you wear the suit?
你以为我不想吗？
You think I don't want to?
是我不能穿
I can't.
我穿了好几年
I spent years wearing it,
它对我的身体产生了副作用
and it took a toll on me.
你是我们唯一的希望
You're our only option.
在霍普失去母亲之前
Before Hope lost her mother,
她看我就像 我是全世界最了不起的人
she used to look at me like I was the greatest man in the world.
现在她看着我眼神只剩下失望
And now she looks at me and there's just disappointment.
对我来说太迟了
It's too late for me,
但你不一样
but not for you.
这是你的机会
This is your chance.
能赢得你女儿崇拜目光的机会
The chance to earn that look in your daughter's eyes.
成为她心目中的英雄
To become the hero that she already thinks you are.
这不是在拯救我们的世界
It's not about saving our world.
而是她们的
It's about saving theirs.
该死 真是好一通说教
Damn. That was a good speech.
斯科特
Scott,
我需要你成为蚁人
I need you to be the Ant-Man.
最佳状态是
In the right hands,
人与衣服合二为一
the relationship between man and suit is symbiotic.
战服拥有力量 人驾驭这种力量
The suit has power. The man harnesses that power.
你需要熟练使用 快速敏捷 最重要的是
You need to be skillful, agile, and above all,
一定要快
you need to be fast.
你需要瞬间
You should be able to shrink and grow
缩小和变大
on a dime.
根据需求缩放自如
So your size always suits your needs.
现在 穿过这个钥匙孔 斯科特
Now dive through the keyhole, Scott.
正常体型加速 穿越时要变小 穿过后再变大
You charge big, you dive small, then you emerge big.
真是没用
Useless.
当你变小时 能量会压缩
When you're small, energy's compressed,
所以百分之一寸大小的拳头
so you have the force of a 200-pound man
约含有九十公斤的人的力量 你就像一颗子弹
behind a fist a 100th of an inch wide. You're like a bullet.
出拳太狠就会杀掉别人 太轻了就像是爱抚
You punch too hard, you kill someone. Too soft, it's a love tap.
话句话说 你应该要知道要怎么出拳
In other words, you have to know how to punch.
我在监狱待了三年 我知道怎么出拳
I was in prison for three years. I know how to punch.
让我瞧瞧
Show me.
- 真差劲 - 你想教我怎么出拳？
- Terrible. - You wanna show me how to punch?
让我瞧瞧…
Show me...
这才叫出拳
That's how you punch.
她等这一刻很久了
She's been looking forward to this.
没开玩笑
No kidding.
霍普在一段困难时期练过武术
Hope trained in martial arts at a difficult time.
噢 所谓"困难时期"就是我母亲去世的时候
Oh, by "difficult time," he means when my mother died.
她死于空难
We lost her in a plane crash.
你不肯告诉我她怎么死的就算了
It's bad enough you won't tell me how she died.
能不能别再跟我撒谎？
Could you please stop telling me that lie?
我们在训练呢
We're working, here.
好的 小公主 我们继续
All right, princess. Let's get back to work.
那是你的手吗？
Were you going for the hand?
我觉得这个调节器有点碍事
You know, I think this regulator is holding me back.
不要动调节器
Do not screw with the regulator.
如果调节器被破坏
If that regulator is compromised,
你会变成亚原子
you would go subatomic.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意味着你会进入量子域
It means that you would enter a quantum realm.
这又是什么意思
What does that mean?
意味着你会永久缩小
It means that you would enter a reality
你会进入到一个时间和空间
where all concepts of time and space
都没有概念
become irrelevant
的现实世界
as you shrink for all eternity.
你所知的和爱的
Everything that you know
所有东西
and love,
将会永远消失
gone forever.
酷 如果它没坏就算了…
Cool. Yeah, if it ain't broke...
你已经了解了战服
You've learned about the suit,
但你还需要了解你了不起的盟友
but you've yet to learn about your greatest allies,
蚂蚁
the ants.
忠诚 勇敢
Loyal, brave,
你这次任务的搭档
and your partners on this job.
长角立毛蚁 通常被称为狂蚁
Paratrechina longicornis. Commonly known as crazy ants.
它们具有闪电般的速度并且能导电
They're lightning fast and can conduct electricity,
可用于攻击敌人的电子系统
which makes them useful to fry out enemy electronics.
你没那么疯狂嘛
You're not so crazy.
嘿
Hey!
你真可爱
You're cute.
一秒钟前太可怕了
That was a lot scarier a second ago.
看起来未来实验室有一套独立的供电系统
It looks like the Futures Lab has its own isolated power supply.
而且全天候都有警卫执勤
There's a security guard posted around the clock.
我们需要你打晕他 然后解除安保系统
We'll need you to take him out to deactivate the security systems.
好的 接下来是谁
Okay, who's next?
帕拉珀尼拉克拉瓦塔
Paraponera clavata.
我知道 子弹蚁 对吧
I know. Bullet ants, right?
在施密特刺痛指数中位列第一
Number 1 on the Schmidt pain index?
嘿 伙计们 还记得我吗 卧室里见过
Hey, guys. Remember me from the bedroom?
黄色战衣被密封在保险库里
The Yellowjacket pod is hermetically sealed,
接近它的唯一途径是一根管子
and the only access point is a tube
我们估计它的直径大约是五毫米
we estimate to be about 5 millimeters in diameter.
为什么我感觉胃里一直犯恶心
Why do I have a sick feeling in my stomach?
管子被激光网保护
The tube is protected by a laser grid,
而且我们只能断电十五秒
and we can only power that down for 15 seconds.
你需要在备用电源恢复前指挥
You're gonna need to signal the crazy ants to blow the servers,
狂蚁破坏服务器 拿到战服
retrieve the suit, and exit the vaults
离开保险库
before the backup power comes on.
宾夕法尼亚弓背蚁
Camponotus pennsylvanicus.
俗称木工蚁
Alternatively known as a carpenter ant.
适合于地面和航空运输
Ideal for ground and air transport.
等等 我认识它
Wait a minute, I know this guy.
我打算叫它"安东蚁"
I'm gonna call him "Ant-thony."
很好 非常好
That's good. That's very good.
因为这次 你真要好好学学
Because this time, you're really gonna
如何控制它
have to learn how to control him.
让它们把糖放进茶杯中
Tell them to put the sugar in the teacup.
哦 你还好吗 我伤到…
Aw! You okay? Did I hurt...
汉克让你到外面进行针对训练
Hank wants you outside for target practice.
战服没有武器 所以我给你做了这些飞镖
The suit has no weapons, so I made you these discs.
红色用来缩小
Red shrinks.
蓝色用来放大
Blue enlarges.
火蚁属
Solenopsis mandibularis.
以它的叮咬闻名
Known for their bite,
火蚁已经进化成为了出色的建筑师
the fire ants have evolved into remarkable architects.
能辅助你进出各种困难的地方
They are handy to get you in and out of difficult places.
你能做到的 斯科特 加油
You can do it, Scott. Come on.
它们不听我的
They're not listening to me.
你必须投入 精准传达你的意思
You have to commit. You have to mean it.
没有捷径 不能欺骗
No shortcuts, no lies.
说话带刺
Throwing insults into the mix
对任何人都没有好处 霍普
will not do anyone any good, Hope.
我们没有时间宠着他
We don't have time for coddling.
我们的焦点应该是帮助斯科特
Our focus should be on helping Scott!
是吗
Really?
这是我们应该聚焦的吗
Is that where our focus should be?
霍普
Hope!
我不懂为什么一开始会来找你
I don't know why I came to you in the first place.
我们不能没有她
We can't do this without her.
哦 上帝啊
Oh, God.
你应该把车门锁上
You gotta lock your doors.
我是说 真的 这附近有很多奇怪的人
I mean, really, there's some weird folks in this neighborhood.
你以为这是闹着玩吗
Do you think this is a joke?
你有没有想过 他让你冒多大的险
Do you have any idea what he's asking you to risk?
你有一个女儿
You have a daughter.
我做这些就是为了她
I'm doing this for her.
你知道吗 当我妈妈过世时 我两周都没有见到他
You know, when my mother died, I didn't see him for two weeks.
他在悲痛之中
He was in grief.
是 我也是 我当时只有七岁
Yeah, so was I, and I was seven.
他从没回来过 从没真正回来过
And he never came back. Not in any way that counted.
他只是把我送去了寄宿学校
He just sent me off to boarding school.
我以为
You know, I thought,
在这种危机关头
with all that's at stake,
也许我们能有机会重归于好
just maybe we might have a chance of making peace.
但即便是现在 他内心还是在排斥我
But, even now, he still wants to shut me out.
他没有排斥你 他信任你
He doesn't wanna shut you out. He trusts you.
那他为什么会找你来
Then why are you here?
这证明他爱你
It proves that he loves you.
霍普 看着我
Hope. Look at me.
我可以是牺牲品
I'm expendable.
这就是我来这里的原因
That's why I'm here.
你现在应该明白
You must have realized that by now.
是我穿着战服 而不是你穿
I mean, it's why I'm in the suit and you're not.
他宁愿输了这场战斗也不愿失去你
He would rather lose this fight than lose you.
真的…
Anyway...
你知道吗 我当时报警的时候
You know, I didn't know you had a daughter
我真不知道你有个女儿
when I called the cops on you.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
凯茜
Cassie.
好美的名字
It's a pretty name.
你必须清除杂念 斯科特
You have to clear your mind, Scott.
你必须让你的思路精准
You have to make your thoughts precise.
这样才行
That's how it works.
想着凯茜
Think about Cassie.
想着你有多想见她 利用这个来集中注意力
About how badly you want to see her. And use that to focus.
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes
专心思考你想让蚂蚁们做什么
and just think about what you want the ants to do.
很好
That's good!
你妈妈当时说服了我
Your mother convinced me
让她加入了我的任务
to let her join me on my missions.
他们叫她黄蜂女
They called her the Wasp.
她对这个很有天分
She was born to it.
我没有一天不在后悔
And there's not a day that goes by
我后悔当初答应了她
that I don't regret having said yes.
那是一九八七年
It was 1987.
分裂主义者劫持了苏联位于库尔斯克的导弹发射井
Separatists had hijacked a Soviet missile silo in Kursk
向美国发射了一枚洲际弹道导弹
and launched an ICBM at the United States.
唯一能进入导弹内部结构的方法
The only way to the internal mechanics
是穿过钛固体
was through solid titanium.
我知道我必须缩小到分子状态穿进去 才能拆除导弹
I knew I had to shrink between the molecules to disarm the missile.
但我的调节器已经遭受了太多损坏
But my regulator had sustained too much damage.
你的母亲
Your mother,
她没有犹豫
she didn't hesitate.
珍妮特 不要
Janet! No!
她关掉了她的调节器
She turned off her regulator
变成了亚原子
and went subatomic
去拆除导弹
to deactivate the bomb.
然后她就走了
And she was gone.
你的妈妈死得很英勇
Your mom died a hero.
那以后的十年间我一直
And I spent the next 10 years
尽我所能的去研究量子领域
trying to learn all I could about the quantum realm.
你是想带她回来
You were trying to bring her back.
但我研究到 我们对此还是一无所知
But all I learned was we know nothing.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
她自己做的决定
She made her choice.
但你为什么没早点告诉我
But why didn't you tell me that sooner?
我是想保护你
I was trying to protect you.
我已经失去了你的母亲
I lost your mother.
我不想再失去你
I didn't mean to lose you, too.
对不起
I'm sorry.
太棒了
This is awesome.
这太棒了
It's awesome, you know?
你们俩在解除心防 伤口在愈合
You guys are breaking down walls, you're healing.
这很重要
It's important.
我破坏了气氛 对吗
I ruined the moment, didn't I?
是的 是的
Yes, you did. Yes.
我去泡杯茶
I'm going to make some tea.
搞定
Nailed it!
好孩子 安东蚁
That's a good boy, Ant-thony.
训练的最后一阶段是秘密入侵
The final phase of your training will be a stealth incursion.
冻死了
It's freezing!
你就不能做一件法兰绒的战服吗
You couldn't make a suit with a flannel lining?
你必须取回这个信号伪装的原型机
You must retrieve this prototype of a signal decoy.
这个装置是我在神盾局时发明的
It's a device that I invented during my S.H.I.E.L.D. days.
我们需要用它来对付克罗斯在未来实验室保险库里
We need it to counteract the transmission blockers
安装的传输阻滞器
that Cross installed in the Futures vault.
它正在纽约州最北部
It's currently collecting dust
霍华德·斯塔克的一处旧仓库里吃灰呢
in one of Howard Stark's old storage facilities in upstate New York.
拿到手应该是小菜一碟
Should be a piece of cake.
你在目标区域上空了
You're over the target area.
现在出发 斯科特
Disengage now, Scott!
A中队 出发
Squadron A, go!
B中队 出发
B, go!
C中队 出发
C, go!
好了 安东蚁 拜托这次别又让我掉下去了
All right, Ant-thony, please don't drop me this time.
感觉从运糖块到这个跨度太大啊
Oh, it feels like a big leap from sugar cubes to this!
保持冷静
Stay calm.
各位 我们可能有麻烦了
Guys? We might have a problem.
汉克 你不是说这是一个旧仓库吗
Hank, didn't you say this was some old warehouse?
这并不是
It's not!
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
- 斯科特 撤退 - 任务中止
- Scott, get out of there. - Abort!
现在中止
Abort now!
不 没事 看起来没人在家
No, it's okay. It doesn't look like anyone's home.
安东蚁 带我去楼顶
Ant-thony, get me to the roof!
他会丢了这套战服的
He's gonna lose the suit.
他会丢了性命的
He's gonna lose his life.
好了 我在目标大楼的楼顶了
All right, I'm on the roof of the target building.
有人回家了 斯科特
Somebody's home, Scott.
下面什么情况 山姆
What's going on down there, Sam?
是猎鹰
It's the Falcon!
感应器有反应 但我没看见什么东西
I had a sensor trip but I'm not seeing anything.
等一下
Wait a second.
中止 斯科特 现在中止
Abort, Scott! Abort now!
没事 他看不见我
It's okay. He can't see me.
我能看见你
I can see you.
他能看见我
He can see me.
嗨 我是斯科特
Hi. I'm Scott.
他刚才说:"嗨 我是斯科特"吗
Did he just say, "Hi, I'm Scott"?
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
首先 我是你的超级粉丝
First off, I'm a big fan.
很感激 那么 你到底是谁
Appreciate it. So, who the hell are you?
我是蚁人
I'm Ant-Man.
"蚁人"？
"Ant-Man"?
怎么了 你没听说过我吗
What? You haven't heard of me?
不 你不会听说过我的
No, you wouldn't have heard of me.
你想告诉我你要什么吗
You wanna tell me what you want?
我想要一件高科技装置
I was hoping I could grab a piece of technology.
借用几天 我会还回来的
Just for a few days. I'm gonna return it.
我需要用它拯救世界 你懂的
I need it to save the world. You know how that is.
对啊 我太懂了
I know exactly how that is.
找到闯入者了
Located the breach.
- 正在抓他 - 对不起了
- Bringing him in. - Sorry about this!
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
闯入者是一个成年男性
Breach is an adult male,
有一种缩身术
who has some sort of shrinking tech.
对不起
Sorry!
真的对不起了
Look, I'm sorry about this. Sorry.
玩够了
That's enough!
安东蚁 帮我一把
Ant-thony! A little help!
我看不到你了
I've lost visual.
他在我背包里
He's inside my pack!
对不起
Sorry!
你好像很了不起
You seem like a really great guy.
千万别让美国队长发现这事 这对我很重要
It's really important to me that Cap never finds out about this.
这事完全是不负责任 还很危险
That was completely irresponsible and dangerous!
你把所有的事都搞砸了
You jeopardized everything!
你拿到了
You got it.
干得好
Well done.
等等
Wait a minute.
你刚刚是在夸我吗
Did you just compliment me?
他在夸我 没错吧
He did, didn't he?
听起来好像是
Kind of sounded like he did.
我以前也很棒 不是吗
I was good, wasn't I?
嘿 我单挑一个复仇者还活着回来了 怎么样
Hey, how about the fact that I fought an Avenger and didn't die?
我们别沉醉于过去里了
Let us not dwell on the past.
我们得完成计划
We gotta finish our planning.
别理他
Don't mind him.
你干得漂亮
You did good.
达伦
Darren.
你怎么进来的
How the hell did you get in here?
汉克 你前门没锁
You left the front door open, Hank.
说真的
It's official.
你老了
You're old.
计划图纸
The plans.
达伦会杀了他的
He will kill him.
大驾光临 有何指教
Well, to what do I owe this pleasure?
我有好消息
I have good news.
是吗
Really?
什么好消息
What's that?
皮姆科技 也就是你创建的公司
Pym Tech, the company you created,
即将成为这世界上
is about to become one of the most
最赚钱的公司之一
profitable operations in the world.
仅仅明天一天的销售额 预计可以达到一百五十亿
We're anticipating $15 billion in sales, tomorrow alone.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
我知道这有点怪 但是我希望你在现场
I know this is odd, but I'd like you to be there.
由你来见证属于我的时刻
This is my moment. I want you to see it.
没问题 达伦
Sure, Darren. Yeah, sure.
我会去的
I'll be there.
你在我身上看到了什么
What did you see in me?
我不懂你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
很多年前 你选择了我
All those years ago, you picked me.
看上我什么
What did you see?
我自己
I saw myself.
那你为什么又放弃我
Then why did you push me away?
因为我发现我们俩太像了
Because I saw too much of myself.
他知道了 他在给你布局
He knows. He's baiting you.
我们得取消计划
We have to call it off.
我们得冒这个险
We're all taking risks.
如果他看见我在这怎么办
What if he saw me here?
不可能 他不可能看见你
He didn't. There's no way.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
达伦 你好
Darren, hi.
霍普 你现在在哪
Hope, where are you right now?
我在家 怎么了
I'm at home. Why?
我刚刚见过汉克了
I just saw Hank.
我从他那得到的只有鄙视 其他的一无所获
I still get nothing but contempt from him.
犯不着为了他动肝火 他就是个糟老头
Don't let him rile you up. He's just a senile old man.
我们需要让所有人全天侯干活
We need to start everyone working around the clock.
让流水线设备投入运行
Get the assembly line up and running.
我还要加强三倍安保
And I'm tripling security.
所有入口处都安装感应器
Full sensors at all entrances
所有外围通风口都要安装微型钢制网罩
and exterior air vents fitted with steel micro-mesh.
很好 好主意
Great. Good idea.
谢谢你 霍普 我很幸运有你在我的团队
Thank you, Hope. I'm so lucky to have you on my team.
他加强了三倍安保 他疯了 他盯上你了
He's tripling security. He's lost his mind, and he's onto you.
但他没有盯上你
But he is not onto you.
他在所有入口都加装全身扫描
He's adding full body scanners to all entrances
还有封锁外围通风口
and closing exterior vents.
我们怎么才能把斯科特弄进去
How are we gonna get Scott inside?
总水管
The water main.
你不能在总水管设安保
You can't add security to a water main.
水压太大 但如果我们能减压
The pressure is too strong, but if we can decrease it,
我就能进去
that's how I get in.
这样就得有人去大楼控制中心
Somebody would have to reach the building's control center
调节水压
to change the water pressure.
汉克和我在那个时候会在克洛斯身旁
Hank and I will be beside Cross.
那我们该怎么去做这事
How are we supposed to do that?
我们得扩大我们的队伍
So we expand our team.
我们需要什么
What do we need?
一个人伪装成保安进入大楼内部
A fake security guard on the inside
由他来调节水压
to de-pressurize the water system,
另一个黑进电源供应系统
somebody else to hack in to the power supply
关闭激光网
and kill the laser grid,
还有一个人负责接应
and a getaway guy.
不不 不行 不要那三个草包 绝对不行
No, no. No, no, no. Not those three wombats. No way.
谢谢你的咖啡 女士
Thank you for the coffee, ma'am.
这事确实少见 很少有人偷完东西 还被盛情款待的
It's not too often that you rob a place and then get welcomed back.
毕竟我们刚来偷过东西
Because we just robbed you.
你知道他是因为偷了一个冰沙机被抓的 是吧
You know that he was arrested for stealing a smoothie machine, right?
是两个冰沙机
Two smoothie machines.
你确定他们能行
Are you sure they can handle this?
我们能搞定 我们很专业
Oh, we can handle it. We're professionals.
原谅我们对你们实在没有什么信心
You'll forgive us if we're not instilled with confidence.
嘿 伙计 大家都应该静下心来放松点
Well, hey, everybody just kick back and relax a little bit, man.
我们的业务能力很高超
We know our business.
这么坚固的鬼房子我们都钻进来了 你说是不是
We broke into this spooky-ass house, didn't we?
我放你进来的
I let you.
我还说 是我让你放我进来呢
Well, one could say that I let you let me.
没问题 他们能搞定
Look, it's okay. They can handle this.
没错 我们能行
Yeah, we can handle it.
- 你能给他证件吗 - 他在公司系统里了
- You got their credentials? - He's in the system.
我在系统里
I'm in the system?
你在系统里
You're in the system.
系统
The system?
我们死定了
Yeah, we're doomed.
好了
All right.
你们得看看这个
There's something you guys need to see.
你到了这个转角
When you get to this corner,
你的左边会有三间办公室
there's gonna be three offices on your left side.
我靠
Damn!
哇喔 真是酷毙了 兄弟
Whoa! That's so cool, bro!
听着 接下来可能有点诡异
Now, look, this is gonna get weird, all right?
怪吓人的 不过没危险
It's pretty freaky, but it's safe.
没有理由会害怕
There's no reason to be scared.
哦 不不 老子才不怕
Oh, no, no. Daddy don't get scared.
- 是吗 - 当然
- Really? - Yeah.
很好
Good.
这是吉普赛人的鬼把戏
This is the work of gypsies.
那是巫术
That's witchcraft.
哇 真神奇
Wow, that's amazing.
就像大卫·科波菲尔的魔术
That's like some David Copperfield shit.
像是魔法
That's some kind of wizardry.
是巫术
This is sorcery!
你怎么做到的 兄弟
How'd you do that, bro?
别吓着了 看看你肩膀
Don't freak out. Look at your shoulder.
啊啊啊
Ahhh!
下去 下去
Get off! Get off!
我以为你不害怕呢
Wait, I thought Daddy didn't get scared!
我给他们每人吃了半片镇定药
I gave them each half a Xanax
汉克给他们解释了战服的原理
and Hank explained the science of the suit to them.
他们马上睡着了
They fell right asleep.
嘿 听着 我想谢谢你
Hey, look, I wanna thank you for...
别谢了
No, please don't.
我们做这事不为别的
We're all doing this for reasons
而是我们有更重要的原因
much bigger than any one of us.
我很开心你还有那么
I'm just glad that you might have
一点点机会去完成这件事
a slight chance of maybe pulling this off.
嘿 谢谢你鼓励我
Hey, thank you, you know, for that pep talk.
说真的 我从最开始鄙视你
You know, the honest truth is, I actually went from despising you
到现在都快喜欢上你了
to almost liking you.
你真的应该去写诗歌
You really should write poetry.
去睡吧 斯科特
Get some sleep, Scott.
好了 都清楚了吧
All right, just so we're clear,
都知道各自的任务了吧
everyone here knows their role, right?
- 戴夫 - 我是开车的
- Dave? - Wheels on the ground.
- 库尔特 - 我负责监视
- Kurt? - Eyes in the sky.
- 路易斯 - 噢 伙计 你懂的
- Luis? - Oh, man, you know it.
知道吗 我爱死穿制服了
You know what? I get to wear a uniform.
- 那就是我要做的 - 路易斯
- That's what's up. - Luis.
对不起 我没问题 我只是有点小兴奋
I'm sorry. I'm good. I'm good. I'm just excited.
再说 你女朋友那么火辣
Plus, your girlfriend's really hot.
你知道 搞得我有点紧张
So, you know, that makes me nervous, too.
女士 你真美
And you are very beautiful, ma'am.
- 噢 天啊 - 她不是我的
- Oh, my Lord. - She's not my...
你知道吗 我突然想到
You know what? I was thinking of
一个战术 我潜进去的时候
a tactic, like when I go undercover.
可以吹口哨 明白我的意思么 混进去
Like a whistling. You know what I'm saying? To like, blend in.
不行 不许吹口哨
No. Don't whistle. No whistling.
这不是安迪·格里菲斯秀 不许吹口哨
It's not The Andy Griffith Show. No whistling.
一区一切正常
All clear in Sector One.
出来
Step out.
一切正常
All clear.
我们就位了
We're set.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
设备已连接
Utilities online.
嘿 你在干嘛
Hey! What are you doing?
老大让我巡视这区 所以我正在巡视
Uh... Boss-man said to secure the area, so I'm securing it.
我就是老大
I'm the boss.
- 喔 - 设备1.3
- Oh. - Utilities 1.3...
水压正在下降
Water level is dropping!
从抽气管爬上去
Coming up on extraction pipe.
看到了
All right, I see it.
来吧 加油 我要上去
All right, come on, I gotta get up there.
对 就这样没错 伙计们
That's it. That's it, guys! Yes!
你们可以的 你们可以做到 加油
Yes! You got it! You got it! Come on!
好了 安东蚁 飞起来
All right, let's fly, Ant-thony.
蚁人已经在楼里了
The Ant-Man is in the building.
皮姆在停车 时间刚刚好
Pym's pulling up. Right on time.
那里停了一辆维多利亚皇冠
Got a Crown Vic right outside there.
有什么问题
This is problem?
维多利亚皇冠是最常见的
Considering the Crown Vic's the most commonly used car
便衣警车 伙计
for undercover cops, man,
这个就是问题
yes, this is problem.
那是皮姆
That's Pym.
哦不
Oh, no.
我在部署子弹蚁
I'm deploying the bullet ants.
名字叫帕拉巴拉拉什么的
Papanera Claire de Merna Merna...
我不记得叫什么了 不过那家伙要有好戏看了
I don't remember what it's called, but I feel bad for this guy.
- 你好 伙计 - 嘿
- What's up, man? - Hey.
啊 啊
Ow! Ow!
看见没 这正是我想说的
See? That's what I'm talking about.
我管它叫 执行重要任务
That's what I call an unfortunate casualty
遇到不幸事故
in a very serious operation.
信号干扰器就位
Signal decoy in place.
也就是说漂亮小姐成功了 斯科特
Mean, pretty lady did good, Scott.
看样子他们要逮捕皮姆了
Looks like Pym's getting arrested.
斯科特 我们有麻烦了
Scott, we have problem.
麻烦 什么麻烦
Problem? What's the problem?
戴夫 戴夫 计划里可不是这样的
Dave! Dave, that's not part of plan!
听我说
Listen to me.
如果我不进去 里面的人会死的
If I don't get into this building, people will die.
真是够戏剧的台词啊
That's awfully dramatic.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
麻烦解决了
Problem solved.
喔
Well...
我看上去怎么样
How do I look?
他来了
There he is.
真准时 来吧
Just in time. Come on.
视网膜12点验证
12-point verification.
防范做得太过了 不觉得吗 达伦
Little over-the-top, don't you think, Darren?
- 确认授权级别 - 安保永远都不嫌多
- Confirming authorization level. - Well, you can never be too safe.
允许进入
Access granted.
不得不佩服你 达伦
Gotta hand it to you, Darren.
你真的做到了
You really did it.
你只知其一不知其二 汉克
And you only know the half of it, Hank.
正在前往第二个目标
Arriving in second position.
极速前进 安东蚁 我们上
All right, top speed, Ant-thony. Let's go!
继续向目的地前进
Proceeding to command position.
我去去就回 安东蚁
I'll be right back, Ant-thony.
好了伙计们 我已就位
All right, guys. I'm in position.
我马上就给蚂蚁们发指令了
I'm gonna signal the ants.
不不不 不
No, no, no, no, no!
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
列队
Assume formation.
来吧 你们这些可爱的小疯子
All right, you cute little crazies,
烧毁服务器吧
let's fry these servers!
我们上 伙计
Let's go get 'em, buddy!
服务器烧毁了
Servers are fried.
数据备份也彻底被抹掉了
Data backup completely erased.
正在赶往粒子室
Heading to the particle chamber.
你好 克罗斯博士
Hello, Dr. Cross.
我的合伙人已经同意你的条款了
My associates have agreed to your terms.
好极了
Wonderful.
卡森先生把我介绍给了这几位先生
Mr. Carson introduced me to these fine gentlemen here.
他们是九头蛇的代表
They're representatives of Hydra.
他们已经改头换面了
They're not what they were.
他们现在做些很有趣的工作
They're doing some interesting work.
而我也很享受这种乐趣
And I'm enjoying myself.
你一直试图向我隐瞒你的研究成果
You tried to hide your technology from me.
可现在它即将在你面前大放异彩
And now it's gonna blow up in your face.
哇哦 我早就猜到你会打我
Wow! I mean, I saw that punch coming a mile away,
但我还以为会是软绵绵的一拳
but I just figured it'd be all pathetic and weak.
那你就猜错了
Well, you figured wrong.
我认得这辆车
I know this van.
有人吗
Anybody home?
好了伙计们 我到了
All right, guys. I'm here.
正在安装炸弹
I'm setting the charges.
干得漂亮 伙计们 接下来就交给我吧
Great job, guys. I'll take it from here.
好样的 安东蚁
Good boy, Ant-thony.
到达最终目的地了
Final position.
伙计们 你们还没有搞定激光网吗
Guys, how we looking on that laser grid?
- 就快了 - 你还差得远呢
- Almost. - No, you're not.
- 马上就好了 - 才没有
- I'm getting close! - No, you're not.
旧金山警察局
San Francisco P.D.!
快从车子里出来
Out of the van!
我知道你们就在里面
I know you're in there!
再快点
Make it go faster.
伙计 别催我
Dude, seriously.
准备跳了 你那边弄好了吗 库尔特
Ready to jump. Do you read, Kurt?
就快好了
So close.
- 举起手来 - 等等 - 别动
- Okay, hold up! - Wait a minute! - Freeze!
刚刚有一个和我长得很像的黑人袭击了我们
There was a black guy that looked exactly like me
然后他把我们塞进了这辆令人作呕的车里
who attacked us and put us in the back of this disgusting van.
- 给我出来 - 好好 我这就出来
- Get out of the van! - Okay, I'm coming.
你慢点啊
Take it easy!
不 我现在还不能离开 快跳
No, I will not move! Go now!
等等
Wait!
什么 你说的等等是什么意思
What? What do you mean, "Wait"?
什么 怎么了
What? What?
你好呀 小家伙
Hey, little guy.
我一直怀疑你在某个地方藏了一套战服
I always suspected you had a suit stored away somewhere.
那问题就来了
Which begs the question,
谁是那个新的蚁人
who is the new Ant-Man?
谁是那个比我更受
Who is the man that my beloved mentor
我敬爱导师信任的人
trusted even more than me?
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
一个勇士
A martyr
一个因为攻破公司的系统而失去了家庭
who took on the system and paid the price,
失去了女儿并拥有献身精神的人
losing his family and his only daughter in the process.
这正是你的最佳人选 汉克
Exactly your kind of guy, Hank!
他逃出了拘留所 没有留下任何线索
He escapes his jail cell without leaving any clue as to how.
然后神奇般的消失了
And then he disappears magically,
尽管他名下穷得一分钱都没有
despite having no money to his name.
可现在 他却给我带来了蚁人战服
And now he brings me the Ant-Man suit.
也只有这件东西能与我的发明抗衡
The only thing that can rival my creation.
达伦 别这样
Darren, don't do this.
如果你把它卖给了这些人
If you sell to these men,
将会掀起一场腥风血雨
it's gonna be chaos.
我已经卖了
I already have.
还是以两倍的价格
And for twice the price,
这得感谢你
thanks to you.
要潜进复仇者联盟的基地可不是件容易的事
It's not easy to successfully infiltrate an Avengers facility.
幸运的是 消息传播得很快
Thankfully, word travels fast.
我会把黄蜂战衣卖给他们
I'll sell them the Yellowjacket,
不过粒子能源我自己留着
but I'm keeping the particle to myself.
战衣不是靠柴油的
They don't run on diesel.
想要补充能源 你还是得来找我
If you want the fuel, you'll have to come to me.
你会怎么称呼那个
What do you call the only man
世界上拥有最厉害的武器的人
who can arm the most powerful weapon in the world?
世界的统治者
The most powerful man in the world.
现在你为我感到骄傲了吗
You proud of me yet?
达伦 现在停手还为时不晚
You can stop this, Darren. It's not too late.
无法挽回了 这已成定局
It's been too late for a long time now.
达伦
Darren!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
他对你还没我对你好
He wasn't any more capable of caring for you than he was for me.
这不是真正的你
This is not who you are.
那些粒子改变了你的头脑
It's the particles altering your brain chemistry.
等等 等等 等一下
Wait! Wait, wait, wait, wait.
你是对的 我应该亲自动手
You're right. I have to be the one to do it.
开始了
Here we go.
放下你的枪
Drop your gun.
那天晚上我去他家里 本来是要杀了他
You know, I came to the house the other night to kill him,
但你在那里
but you were there.
你失去理智了 我可以帮你 把枪放下
You're sick and I can help you. Just put the gun down.
我那时并不想杀你的
I wasn't ready to kill you then,
但现在我愿意了
but I think I am now!
快把枪放下
Drop your gun now!
你站错了队伍了 霍普
You picked the wrong side, Hope.
爸爸
Dad!
汉克 不
Hank, no.
不 汉克
No, Hank.
汉克 听着 你会没事的
Hank? Listen, you're gonna be okay.
你会好起来的
All right? You're gonna be just fine.
把战服脱下来 不然我就一枪打爆你的头 再扒了它
Take the suit off, or I'll blow your brains out and peel it off.
突发事件 我们在皮姆科技公司
We got a 10-33 at Pym Tech.
请求立即增援
Request immediate backup!
快走
Go, go, go!
送我到楼顶
Get me to the roof.
把消息传下去
And radio ahead.
我要确保直升机能随时起飞
I want to make sure the helicopter is ready to take off.
你们两个
You two,
从那库房里出来的 格杀勿论
kill anything that comes out of that vault!
爸爸 你还能动吗
Dad, can you move?
我们得把他从这里弄出去
We need to get him out of here.
快 快去拿那套战衣
Go get that suit.
嘿 斯科特
Hey, Scotty.
嘿 我有救到你的命了吗
Hey, did I save your life?
斯科特
Scotty?
谢谢你 路易斯
Thank you, Luis.
- 我们是好人 对吧 - 是的
- Are we the good guys? - Yeah.
我们真的是好人 对吗
We're the good guys, right?
嗯 我们是好人
Yeah, we're the good guys.
这感觉有点奇怪
Feels kinda weird, you know.
嗯 但我们还有任务没做完
Yeah, but we're not done yet.
在这栋楼爆炸之前撤出去
Get out of here before this place blows!
见鬼 还有那家伙
Damn it! That guy.
嘿 我们得离开这
Hey! We're getting out of here!
炸弹已经设定好了
The charges are set.
我们得尽快找到出去的方法
We've gotta find a way out of here. And fast.
别担心
Don't worry.
我死不了
I'm not gonna die.
你也是
And neither are you.
这可不仅仅是一个钥匙扣
It's not a keychain.
现场一片混乱 还有多次枪击
It's total chaos in here! Multiple shots fired!
还多了一辆坦克
And there's a tank.
帮帮忙
A little help!
我来吧
I got it.
我们需要医生
We need a doctor!
我们接到他了
We've got him.
谢谢你
Thank you.
快走
Let's go!
安东蚁
Ant-thony!
走
Go!
你会后悔的
You're gonna regret that.
等一下 从那车里出来
Wait a minute! Get out of that van!
- 什么 - 快从那车里出来
- What? - Get out of that van!
这里太吵了 还有辆坦克 我听不见你说什么
It's too loud, there's a tank. I can't hear you!
你疯了吗 放下枪
Are you crazy? Put the gun down!
窗户坏了
The windows!
你真以为抢走了战衣就能阻止未来吗
Did you think you could stop the future with a heist?
我做的可不止抢战衣
It was never just a heist!
把枪放下
Put the gun down!
好 我看到他了 就在那 快 快
Okay, I got him, I got him. There he is! Go, go, go!
我们得找个地方降落
We gotta set her down somewhere.
我要让你粉身碎骨
I'm gonna disintegrate you!
正在播放治疗乐队的粉身碎骨
Playing Disintegration by the Cure.
快报警
Call 911!
没事了
It's okay.
别动 举起手来
Freeze! Put your hands up! Get them up!
斯科特
Scott?
帕克斯顿 你一定要听我解释
Paxton, you have to listen to me!
帕克斯顿 快掉头 让我回去
Paxton, turn around! Take me back!
我是在带你回去 回监狱去
I am taking you back. To prison.
那后院里有个东西必须要销毁
There's something in that backyard that needs to be destroyed.
在灭蚊灯里 有…
In the bug zapper. There...
你别再胡说八道了 你的幻想太离谱了
You need to desist right now! Your delusions are out of hand.
各小组注意
All units, we have a 2-36
温特街840号发生紧急事件
in progress at 840 Winter Street.
- 凯茜 - 那是我的家
- Cassie! - That's my house.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
帕克斯顿 让我帮忙
Paxton, let me help!
呆在这别动
Don't move.
让我帮你
Let me help!
玛姬 发生了什么
Maggie! What's going on?
他抓住了凯茜
He's got Cassie!
- 谁抓住了凯茜 亲爱的 - 那个东西
- Who's got Cassie, honey? - That thing.
- 什么东西 - 我不知道 我不知道
- Thing? - I don't know! I don't know!
你是怪兽吗
Are you a monster?
我看起来像怪兽吗
Do I look like a monster?
我要找我爸爸
I want my daddy!
我也要找你爸爸
I want your daddy, too.
你总算来了
There you are.
爸爸 是你吗
Daddy, is that you?
嗨 小花生
Hi, peanut.
你怎么不找一个跟你一样大小的人当对手呢
Why don't you pick on someone your own size?
现在你跑去哪了 小家伙
Now, where did you go, little guy?
找到你了
There you are.
不止是我哦
Not just me!
该死
Damn it!
快 快上
Go! Go!
斯科特需要我们 你懂吗
Scotty needs us, you know what I'm saying?
没有什么能阻挡我们
Ain't nothing gonna stop us.
倒车
Back it up.
慢慢倒车
Back it up, slow.
好的
Yeah.
- 倒车 - 好
- Back it up. - Yeah.
- 倒车吧 - 行
- Back it up. - Okay.
- 我们只是倒个车而已 - 是的
- We just back it up, okay? - That's it.
- 倒吧 - 对
- Back it up. - That's right.
在倒吗
Backin' up?
在 倒着呢
Yep, just backin' up.
嗯 就默默倒车吧
No, no. Just back it up.
你侮辱了我 斯科特
You insult me, Scott.
你的存在就是对我的侮辱
Your very existence is insulting to me.
知道吗 如果你再大点就更容易打到你了
You know, it'd be much easier to hit you if you were bigger.
是啊 我同意
Yeah, I agree.
凯茜
Cassie!
我要让你见识一下你是多么的微不足道
I'm gonna show you just how insignificant you are.
凯茜 我来了
Cassie! I'm coming!
你们家的狗长得可真任性
That's a messed-up looking dog.
我要毁掉
I'm gonna destroy
你所珍爱的一切
everything you love.
不准动 旧金山警局
Freeze! S.F.P.D.
我进不去
I can't break through.
这可是钛合金 蠢货
It's titanium, you idiot!
- 带她离开这 - 来吧
- Get her out of here. - Come on.
对不起 亲爱的
Sorry, sweetheart.
你得为你爸爸犯下的错付出代价
You have to help Daddy pay for his mistakes.
- 躲在我后面 好吗 - 好
- You stay behind me, okay? - Okay.
躲在我后面
Stay behind me.
我必须缩小到分子级才能进去
I'm gonna have to shrink between the molecules to get in there.
离我们远点
Get away from us!
爸爸 救命
Daddy, help!
我爱你 凯茜
I love you, Cassie.
爸爸 你在哪
Daddy, where are you?
你会进入次原子域
You could go subatomic.
噢 不
Oh, no.
你会进入一个时间和空间的概念
You would enter a reality
都会化为虚无的领域
where all concepts of time and space...
所有时间和空间的意义都将成为泡影
All concepts of time and space become irrelevant.
… 所有时间和空间都将成为泡影
all concepts of time and space become irrelevant.
爸爸 快回来
Come back, Daddy!
… 你将永远都在缩小
as you shrink for all eternity.
你所了解的
Everything that you know
和所珍爱的一切
and love,
都会化为乌有
gone forever.
爸爸 你在哪
Daddy, where are you?
你在哪
Where are you?
- 爸爸 - 凯茜
- Daddy! - Cassie.
快回来 爸爸
Come back, Daddy!
不要乱动调节器
Do not screw with the regulator!
爸爸
Daddy!
我好爱你
I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
非常爱
So much.
知道吗 屋顶开了个个大洞
You know, there's a big hole in the roof.
很抱歉
Sorry.
- 她还好吗 - 嗯 她没事
- Is she all right? - Yeah, she's fine.
妈妈
Mommy!
她没事 她没事
She's fine, she's fine.
斯科特 拜托
Scott, please.
你什么都不记得了吗
You don't remember anything?
汉克 我真不记得了
Hank. I don't.
总得有点什么吧
There must be something else.
我猜可能以人类的思维
Well, I suppose the human mind
目前还无法理解这样的体验
just can't comprehend the experience,
但你做到了
but you made it.
你进去了
You went in,
然后活着出来了
and you got out.
简直不可思议
It's amazing.
斯科特
Scott,
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
好好休息
Get some rest.
还有可能吗
Is it possible?
这是什么时候发生的
When did this happen?
并没有发生什么
Nothing's happening.
等等 还是发生了点什么的吧
Whoa. Hold on. Something's kind of happening.
如果真是这样的话
Well, if that's the case,
再补我一枪吧
shoot me again.
是啊 我都不知道你在干嘛
Yeah. I don't know what you were doing,
突然抓住我就开始亲
grabbing and kissing me like that.
我自己也受到了惊吓
I'm a little surprised myself.
我有事先走了 回见 汉克
I have to get somewhere. I'll see you later, Hank.
真是的 霍普
Really, Hope.
- 斯科特 - 啊
- Scott. - Yeah?
- 你就扯吧 - 好吧
- You're full of shit. - Oh, yeah.
斯科特 我今天跟我队长见了一面
Scott, I met with my captain today.
他想要你出狱那天晚上的报告
He wanted a report on the night that you got out of jail.
监视器出了点问题
Something happened with the cameras.
有些线路被烧了
Some circuits got fried.
不过我告诉他你完全是走正当程序出狱的
But I told him that you were processed correctly.
真的吗
Really?
是啊
Well, yeah.
总不能因为一点技术上的小故障 就把凯茜的爸爸又送回监狱 对吗
Can't be sending Cassie's dad back to jail on a technical glitch, right?
谢谢你 帕克斯顿
Thank you, Paxton.
我很感动
I'm blown away.
谢谢你为凯茜做的一切
Thank you for everything you do for Cassie.
那是我的荣幸
Well, that's my pleasure.
不过 这一回 我是为了你
But, no. This one, I did for you.
- 有点尴尬 - 是啊
- This is awkward. - Yeah.
是啊
Yeah.
我在想 经历了这些事之后 我们该说点什么
I mean, what do we even talk about after all of that?
- 噢 我知道 - 什么
- Oh, I know. - What?
我今天翻了人生中第一个跟斗
I did my first cartwheel today.
什么
What?
是的 她练习翻跟斗都已经一个星期了呢
Yeah. She has been practicing all week.
但今天终于到了见证奇迹的时刻
But today was the magic day.
我拿手机录下来了 看
I recorded it on my phone. Here.
不 这不可能是凯茜 这才不是你呢
No, that can't be Cassie. That's not you.
- 就是她 - 就是我
- Yeah, it is. - Yeah, it is.
这就是个专业的体操运动员 不可能是你
This is a professional gymnast. There is no way that's you.
是 真的是她
Yeah, that's her.
真乖
Good boy.
这真是太不可思议了 小花生
Sweetie, that's pretty amazing, peanut.
不好意思
Sorry.
工作上的事
It's work.
喂
Yeah.
好吧
All right.
这样吧 直接说 只说事实
Here's the deal. Just give me the facts.
只要事实 不要别的
Just the facts. Only the facts.
深呼吸 集中注意力 长话短说
Breathe. Focus. Keep it simple.
好 没问题 没问题 来吧
No, no, no. No doubt, no doubt. Okay.
我跟我表哥伊格纳西奥在一个艺术博物馆
So, I'm at this art museum with my cousin Ignacio, right?
那是一场抽象表现主义的展览
And there was this, like, abstract expressionism exhibit.
但是你懂我的 其实我更喜欢新立体派主义的 是吧
But you know me, I'm more like a Neo-Cubist kind of guy, right?
但那有一副罗斯科的画简直棒呆了 伙计 天哪
But there was this one Rothko that was sublime, bro! Oh, my God!
路易斯
Luis.
好吧 不好意思
Okay, sorry. Sorry.
你知道我一兴奋就有点话痨的
You know, I just get excited and stuff.
不过 总之 伊格纳西奥告诉我
But anyway, Ignacio tells me,
我昨晚在斯波特酒吧遇见了一个
"Yo, I met this crazy-fine writer chick
超级辣的美女作家 简直太辣了
"at the Spot last night. Like fine-fine.
辣呀辣呀 辣得都快惹火了
"Like crazy-stupid fine." And he
然后他去跟酒保说
"goes up to the bartender and goes,
瞧我泡的妞 你懂我什么意思吗
"Look at the girl I'm with. You know what I'm sayin'?
她太他妈辣了 是吧
"She's crazy-stupid fine, right?"
然后酒保说 是啊 真他妈辣
The bartender's all like, "Yeah, crazy-stupid fine."
然后这个美女作家告诉伊格纳西奥
So this writer chick tells Ignacio,
哟 我算得上是狗仔界的老大了
"Yo, I'm like a boss in the world of guerrilla journalism,
我跟无数小道消息来源者都有密切的联系
"and I got mad connects with the peeps behind the curtains,
你懂我什么意思吧 伊格纳西奥说 真的吗
"you know what I'm saying?" Ignacio's like, "For real?"
然后她说 是啊 你知道吧
And she's like, "Yeah, you know what,
我可不能告诉你我的联系人是谁
I can't tell you who my contact is,
因为他与复仇者们共事
because he works with the Avengers."
不是吧
Oh, no.
是啊 这家伙听起来可是个狠角色 伙计
Yeah, and this dude sounds like a badass, man.
他找到她然后说
Like, he comes up to her and says,
我要找一个道上的新人
"Yo, I'm looking for this dude who's new on the scene,
一个能快速完成任务
"who's flashing his fresh tack,
有着爆炸般行动力的人 懂了吗 你认识这种人吗
"who's got, like, bomb moves, right? Who you got?"
她说 现如今我们什么样的人都有
And she's like, "Well, we got everything
有能跳的
nowadays. We got a guy who jumps.
能飞的 能爬墙的
We got a guy who swings, we got a guy who crawls up the walls.
你得更具体点
You gotta be more specific."
然后他说 我在找一个能缩小的家伙
And he's like, "I'm looking for a guy that shrinks."
当时我就觉得 我靠 我瞬间紧张了起来
And I'm, like, "Damn!" I got all nervous
因为我还为你保守着大秘密呢 伙计
cause I'd keep mad secrets for you, bro.
所以我就问伊格纳西奥
So I asked Ignacio,
这个狠角色 是不是告诉这个超辣的美女作家
"Did the badass tell the stupid-fine writer chick
要她让你告诉我 他在找蚁人
"to tell you to tell me, because I'm tight with Ant-Man,
因为我是蚁人的好哥们
that he's looking for him?"
然后呢 他说什么了
And? What'd he say?
他说 是的
He said, "Yes."
《蚁人》
我想给你看点东西
There's something I want to show you.
我意识到力量是无法被毁灭的
I realized you can't destroy power.
我们能做的只有保证它被对的人利用
All you can do is make sure that it's in the right hands.
这是你妈和我共同研发的
This is an advanced prototype
升级版战衣原型
that your mother and I worked on together.
她还没来得及穿上它
She never got to use it.
但现在我明白了… 其实这是我们为你而研发的
But now I realize that we were... We were working on it for you.
也许是时候完成它了
Maybe it's time we finished it.
太是时候了
It's about damn time.
嗨 队长
Hey, Cap!
这要是几周前就好办得多了
This would have been a lot easier a week ago.
- 如果我们告诉托尼… - 他不会相信我们的
- If we call Tony... - He won't believe us.
就算他信了
Even if he did...
天知道协议上有没有哪条规定不让他帮忙的
Who knows if the Accords will let him help.
只能靠我们自己了
We're on our own.
或许不用
Maybe not.
我认识一个家伙
I know a guy.